Hi there. So far,
大家好到目前为止
you've been introduced to the concept of
你已经学习了
a factor and the framework of the multifactor model.
因子和多因子模型框架
We've also touched upon how in practice we defined some factors
我们还大致介绍了在实践中如何将某些因子
as risk factors and other factors as alpha factors.
定义为风险因子 将其他因子定义为 alpha 因子
In this lesson, we will focus on
在这节课 我们将侧重于风险因子
risk factors and the fundamentals of the risk factor model.
以及风险因子模型的基本知识
Risk factor models are used to describe the volatility or risk of
风险因子模型根据风险因子的变化
assets such as stocks based on the movements of the risk factors.
描述股票等资产的波动性或风险
The goal of a risk factor model is to measure,
风险因子模型的目标是衡量和控制投资组合
control and possibly neutralize a portfolio's exposure to major sources of risk.
对大型风险来源的暴露度 并且使投资组合对主要风险敞口保持中性
In order to achieve this goal,
为了实现这种目标
we need a way to model the portfolio's risk in terms of the common risk factors.
我们需要用一些公共风险因子对投资组合的风险进行建模
To model a portfolio's risk,
为了对投资组合的风险建模
we want to model individual asset variances and
我们需要用风险因子
pairwise asset covariances in terms of these risk factors.
对单个资产的方差和一对资产间的协方差建模
To model asset variance and covariance in terms of risk factors,
为了用风险因子对资产方差和协方差建模
we need a couple pieces of information;
我们需要获得一些信息
the variances and covariances of risk factors,
包括风险因子的方差和协方差
the factor exposures which measure how exposed each asset is to each risk factor,
因子暴露度 即每个资产对各个风险因子的暴露度
and the specific variance of each asset that is not explained by the risk factors.
以及风险因子无法解释的特定资产方差
To calculate the variances and covariances of the risk factors,
为了计算风险因子的方差和协方差
we also need to calculate the returns of the factors which are called the factor returns.
我们还需要计算因子的收益率 称为因子收益率
We'll also make use of the asset returns which will help us either estimate
我们还会利用资产收益率
the factor exposures or the factor returns depending on the type of risk model.
估算因子暴露度或因子收益率 取决于风险因子的模型
We can then use these pieces of information to
然后 我们可以利用这些信息
estimate the specific variants of each asset.
估算每个资产的具体方差
To start off, we also should decide what factors we'll use in our model.
首先 我们还需要决定在模型中使用哪些因子
By the way, don't worry if these terms don't look familiar yet,
顺便提下 如果你不熟悉这些术语 也没关系
you'll see a couple of ways of getting all the pieces that go into a risk model.
你将在后面见到风险模型的各个组成部分
So along the way,
在此过程中
you'll see what these words mean.
你将知道这些术语的含义
We'll begin with the motivation for using risk factor models.
首先我们需要确定使用风险因子模型的动机
Factor models have some benefits over
与直接使用单个资产的协方差对投资组合风险建模相比
modelling portfolio risk directly from the covariances of its individual assets.
因子模型具有一些优势
Next, we will cover the framework for the risk factor model.
接下来 我们将介绍风险因子模型的框架
The risk factor model attempts to explain the variance of
风险因子模型尝试将投资组合的方差
a portfolio as the sum of two parts;
解释为两个部分的和
the variance that can be attributed to
即公共风险因子可以解释的方差
the common risk factors plus variance that is not explained by those risk factors.
加上这些风险因子无法解释的方差
I just want to point out that risk factor modeling combined with
注意 风险因子建模和 alpha 因子建模
alpha factor modeling are both crucial to successful portfolio optimization.
对成功的投资组合优化来说都很关键
Just as a car needs both a brake pedal and an accelerator or
就像汽车既需要刹车踏板 又需要加速装置
a good basketball team needs both a good defense and also a good offense.
成功的篮球队既需要好的防守球员 又需要好的进攻球员
An effectively optimized portfolio needs to both control risk using risk factors,
有效优化的投资组合既需要通过风险因子控制风险
while seeking higher than expected returns using alpha factors.
又需要利用 alpha 因子获得超出预期的收益率